Guide to the Richard Root papers, 1957-2008.
Root, Richard papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Richard Root papers, 1957-2008.
14-35-4058
Root, Richard
15.4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, research materials,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, subject files and research focused on community ecology with special reference to the structure and evolution of insect-plant associations, evolutionary ecology, population dynamics, and dispersal of phytophagous insects and Root's career in the Dept. of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Root was emeritus professor in the Dept. of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology. He received his B.S. in 1958 from the University of Michigan and his Ph.D. in 1964 from the University of California, Berkeley.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, subject files and research focused on community ecology with special reference to the structure and evolution of insect-plant associations, evolutionary ecology, population dynamics, and dispersal of phytophagous insects and Root's career in the Dept. of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology.
Includes research notes on goldenrods, mowed grids and the Cayuga Survey.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Root, Richard; Cayuga Survey.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology.
Subjects:
Goldrenrods.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 1-4 and 7 are restricted until September 2025.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence - A-E, 1957-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1-30)
- Correspondence - B, 1981-2006 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Correspondence - Eck-Kar, 1957-2004 (Box 2, Folder 1-24)
- Correspondence - Kin-Pa, 1957-2004 (Box 3, Folder 1-28)
- Correspondence - Par-Smith, E., 1957-2004 (Box 4, Folder 1-22)
- Correspondence - Smith, Lincoln-Z, 1957-2008 (Box 7, Folder 3-23)
- Guild Concept, 1998-2002 (Box 1, Folder 24-27)
- Grants and Proposals, additional Correspondence, 1956-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1-42)
- Grant Files, 1966-1992 (Box 6, Folder 1-13)
- Cayuga Survey - Raw Data, 1981-1992 (Box 8)
- Cayuga Survey (1993-1998) and Mowed Grid (1979-1994) - Raw Data, 1979-1998 (Box 9)
- Mowed Grid - Raw Data, 1995-1998 (Box 10)
- Lectures, 1972-2001 (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous Teaching Material, 1987-2003 (Box 10)
- Insect Ecology Teaching Material, 1973-1993 (Box 10)
- Seminars, 1962-1974 (Box 10)
- Cornell and Organization of Tropical Studies, 1966-1995 (Box 10)
- Seminars - Bio Science 661, 1965-1967 (Box 11)
- Insect Ecology Labs and Lecture Notes - Ent 400, 1973-2001 (Box 11)
- General Ecology Lecture Notes, 1970-1990 (Box 11)
- Field Ecology Course, 1968-2002 (Box 12)
- General Ecology Course, 1963-1982 (Box 12)
- Research on Solidago Patula, 1994-2003 (Box 12)
- Seminars, such as Patch, Community and Competition, 1959-1993 (Box 12)
- Gnatcatcher Study - Raw Data, 1960s (Box 12)
- Field Ecology Notes, 1984-2002 (Box 13)
- Field Ecology Appendices, 1984-1997 (Box 13)
- Ecology and Environment (General Ecology) Lecture Notes, 1990s (Box 13)
- Solidago Research, Lectures, 1979-2003 (Box 13)
- Goldenrod Research, 1979-1986 (Box 14)
- Gowan Correspondence, 1971-1986 (Box 14)
- Pesticide Information, 1990s (Box 14)
- Radiation Dump Clones, Maps, 1986-1996 (Box 14)
- Solidago Insect Fauna Research, 1980-1986 (Box 14)
- Journal with notes from Archbold, 1981-1988; 1990-1998 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Journal with notes from Archbold - Solidago Chapmanni, 1990-2002 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Field Notes, 1957-1976 (Box 15-16)